socializing is a three-part
conversations we spend 15 minutes
talking about what it currently looks
like in this case in media entertainment
and then 15 minutes talking about what
we'd like it to look like an hour ideal
version of a ideal world version however
far in the future that needs to be and
then we spend half an hour talking about
but 10,000 people and $100,000 could
actually do right now in this in this
space come up with an actual adjacent
possible so for the first part we
usually just end up ranting Eric would
you like to start down usually start
right good I can rant on media and
entertainment no problem get the rant
out of the way and then we can get down
to the solution I'm not going first
that's totally valid do want me to go
first Eric since usually all right oh
media and entertainment particularly
this is a weird one because it's life
imitates art and art imitates life so
how much is how much it is art responds
there we go there we go so having a
levitate art it's funny Eric just let
let us let us cigarette because that's
part of like back in the was it the 80s
when media stopped allowing or stopped
having cigarettes but everywhere it
actually did go down a fairway is one of
my things that always I get really
annoyed in media when they carry around
those coffee cups that are disposable my
mom gets really annoyed because they're
light mints so it's just like they're
not even full of coffee at least filled
a bowl of water like how hard would it
be for all the cops to carry reusable
ones because then people would start to
mimic it but they get the cops don't
carry your usable ones so they want it
to look real so then Pete and then
people mimic the what people are
carrying around and it ends up being
self perpetuating there's a lot of I was
thinking about in the difference between
technology and and media entertainment
so much money is spent when you have a
new film and and I live in Vancouver
where like city streets are shut down so
that so they can film it and yet it's so
much risk and so much labor for
something that may or may not succeed
the diversity is getting better with
and movies and media there's a lot more
people of color and disability and our
divergence and stuff that's that's shown
but way less than representation and a
lot of that has to do with profit and
I'm sketching here the same time they're
just a lot like a lot of it being for
profit but of course it's for profit
it's entertainment and how important is
entertainment I shadow yes like I I
absolutely love watching sorry to chide
like me to do I mean that you having I
feel like my thoughts are very
distractive day and I might just end it
there and let someone else rat for a
while I'm sure I'll come up with a lot
but it's like a lot of money to take on
risk when I really enjoy media but I
wish that we could kind of vote on what
gets made like I wish this is all good
comment section okay anyway would anyone
else like to share what's going on in
the media and entertainment and what you
currently do for it how you you know
what you like about it and don't like
about it I'll go just because I want to
pick up on your point about smoking and
when ads for smoking were banned and
they were no longer allowed to sponsor
sporting events and all of that kind of
thing the tobacco companies what they
did instead was they encouraged
characters in movies to smoke more and
if you look at the incidence of smoking
in movies since tobacco advertising was
banned it's gone through the roof so the
product placement you know putting using
art as advertising conduits you know
what I mean this is this is one of the
things that kind of makes me a little
bit ill then as that it's not restricted
to the background in product placement
exists in TV shows and movies all over
the place a big source of revenue for
the makers of movies and you know it
must impinge to some degree on the
artistic process obvious is a continuum
here in some cases it impinges a lot
more than others right but for sure and
so I guess there's the core of my rent
is that money and profit really have no
business in the in in the world of art
and media and entertainment right stuff
she made simply because it's good and
it's fun to make and people want to make
it and people want to see it or listen
to it or
or whatever it might be and as soon as
you inject money into it and the
requirement to get back your investment
right and the requirement to fund it you
know find funding for it as soon as you
go out looking for people to fund your
project they now expect to have some
kind of input into the project right and
once again the artistic integrity of the
thing itself is compromised so yeah
whatever the whatever I know this is
slightly jumping here but whatever the
future of art and media is to be it has
to somehow divorce itself from this
whole need to make profit right and it's
made because it's good and people want
to get involved in the project and
that's the barrier not that you can't
raise the money but people aren't
interested because it looks like
right and as simple as that so yeah I
guess I'll stop there
sure Laura Daniel do you wanna do you
wanna share I do have notes here I feel
like I rambled for way too long and said
nothing when I did buy-in so I can go
honestly I haven't thought about this
topic a whole lot so I'll be honest
about that I think that media means so
many different things
I have studied social media a lot more
and I'm kind of more knowledgeable and
like understanding some types of
problems and potential solutions there
but on the whole you know like I say
there's different types of media there's
as print media there's there's pamphlets
then there's movies there's TV so this I
think it's important to think about like
what different areas obviously I'm not
that like I don't have like a rant I'm
not that emotional about topic I do like
what was mentioned about like you know
the disposable cups or the smoking thing
we are it is a way to influence culture
we're giving folks who have these great
big platforms on now like you know TV
but I don't know how many people watch
TV Netflix or whatever say you have a
popular show that's like popular just
for the sake of it look I don't really
have a problem with that like people
seem to like being entertained but now
you have this moment you have moments
for teachable moments and we can
influence culture positively or
negatively through those teachable
moments like you say you know having
more diversity having more diverse types
of people types of relationships you
know having having LGBT relationships on
shows and things you know that whole
gamut like so there's opportunities to
show more holistic moments of humanity
getting people like outside the box so
can that be framed inside of like a show
that's just geared on pure entertainment
comedy or something like yeah it seems
like there's opportunities for that
lately so we've got like these teachable
moments lately I do think a lot about
our waste problem and I recently watched
that what is it called the planet of
humans that documentary that came out
and so like as an engineer type that was
pretty eye-opening I'm kind of like the
renewable energy stuff that's going on I
you know I want to fact-check some
things but like point--is seems like
much of our solutions in waste have to
come with reducing what we're spending
and doing and so if I'm emotional about
any of that or something it's more like
Wow when you look at all these
television show
and movies the production cost not just
on monetary side but the stuff all the
costumes all of the energy you know
petroleum or whatever that's put in to
these things so they're just these
moments and time that get recorded and
then poof it's gone I mean I don't know
what happens to all that stuff I mean
hopefully studio spaces get reused but
flying equipment all around the world
for these shoots and everything it seems
it reminds me a little bit of sports
like it seems like a total waste of our
time and energy so maybe that's part two
I guess the other thing that comes to
mind is the difficulty in the access so
there's like moments there's like
teachable moments and advertising inside
of existing shows television and movies
but it also looks like um the people who
have had all the monetary resources for
the past hundred years they're the ones
deciding what gets put in front of
people next you know if I have this now
there's always exceptions and there's
like little breakout things that they
never expected to do well but for the
most part they're designing things that
will just sell the most and so yeah when
you think of what advertisement am I
gonna see for the next show that's
coming up whatever that might be it's
it's almost like lobbyists or something
it's like they're they're not heavily
advertising things that are important
and things that actually like would be
good for people they're heavily
advertising like keeping the status quo
going pandering to consumption and all
sorts of
cultural tropes that we might think are
no longer helpful but they like
romanticize these things status and and
wealth and was I thinking about a couple
years ago how like Daniel I'm just gonna
so I just want to give a shout time you
share before we go on to the next the
next portion and then we can have a
little bit more of an open conversation
about what's currently going on in the
media Charlie would you or do want to
give you the opportunity you don't have
to okay um I guess I have a couple quick
stories I'll try to make it really short
um I I know I'm not an expert or
anything but I know there's something to
be said like our brains can't tell the
difference between what we see and what
we're really experiencing so there's
something very powerful in that and I
just wanted to share like two things in
my life that I the first one I remember
was I used to watch I don't know tons of
cartoons and there'd always be somebody
that was like running around with a bat
and hitting somebody else on the head or
like a log or something like that and I
remember being at a friend's house and I
was I don't know maybe five kind of
young and their dad had just come home
from crab fishing so he'd been gone for
months and everyone was excited it was
kind of a party and we were running
around the house and he was kind of
chasing us and I remember I grabbed a
bat and got up on this top of a dresser
and waited till he came in the door and
I whacked him on the head I thought it
was hilarious and it wasn't and people
got really pissed off and I didn't I
didn't have I couldn't understand why it
wasn't funny when I did it and that was
maybe my first time I realized oh like
things are a little like not really what
you believe but as a child you can't you
don't have that discernment so that
really points to all the advertising
around children right now just really
terrible and a lot of it is does go to
this waste or overconsumption idea so we
start there really young teaching them
about things that I don't know just
there is no inner there's no connection
with what they're seeing but they
definitely want these things because
they look so desirable my second thing
is I was much older
and I was working in a French spa and so
in 2000 there was a it was an election
year and I remember working in the print
shop it's dealing with these politicians
that would come in and want me to make
these pamphlets Daniel you were talking
about there's different types of media
so this is print and they would come in
and they wouldn't want me to make these
pamphlets it's just showing how great
they are family people great values but
they're real assholes
and I'm empathic very in tune to how
people's real personality is and it was
so like it went on I don't know eight
months or something of this political
season we're making all this political
advertising and a war on me so much I
felt like this was just a propaganda
machine and we were just a regular print
shop but we did get because we were a
union shop we said their reunion but we
really weren't yet we got a lot of the
politicians because they wanted that
Union bug on their flyers and it was
drastic to meet these people and then to
see their flyers coming to me in the
mail and how much money they spend on it
just outrageous amounts of money of
advertising and it felt like straight
lies it just did not feel like who this
person really was so those are my two
kind of media things that come up for me
right now and I will let us move on to
the next one yeah so that was like
perfect timing 50 minute mark so now we
move on to the part where we can each
talk about what we would like it to look
like so it's specifically media and
entertainment
what would the entertainment sector of
the media look like in five ten a
hundred years under your ideal world and
our visions in no way need to match they
don't need to counteract er but if you
want to add on someone else's you're
able to after they share but what is
your version of entertainment look like
in however long and good to look like I
I have a story to kick this off with
when I was god I must have been about
ten years old something like that when
the first Star Wars movie came out right
and like a lot of other kids of my age
and older and my parents and
some other adults I completely fell in
love with this film right
and then there was Empire Strikes Back
which was even better than The Return of
the Jedi knew it wasn't as good as the
first see but it was still you know
still liked it I was a bit older didn't
like the Ewoks that much blah blah blah
but anyway that franchise obviously is
one of the biggest in movie history
right in fact was the biggest until
Marvel came along and they went on to
make the three prequels which were
dreadful and then part seven eight and
nine which set new standards in
unintelligible follow and all kinds of
spin-offs right there's the Mandalorian
and there's the cartoons and there's
pinball machines and bla bla bla bla bla
bla bla bla bla I mean this is this is a
giant business right so anyway what I'm
driving at with all this is sounds like
a rant right but it's actually not what
I'm driving at with all of this is the
entertainment and I know we're focusing
particularly on entertainment right
rather than information that's the next
one right and so the end I think to a
certain extent they're inseparable from
each other right but but that's that's
another conversation the media the
entertainment industry of the future
would look like an environment in which
people made films because because George
Lucas had storyboards for decades right
I mean he had this story bouncing around
his head but literally decades before he
finally managed it you know it was a
labor of love it was a and so the
industry needs to be that right people
producing stuff from that and not as
straightaway happens look at the matrix
right another brilliant film a
long-standing project right and there
and then money came into it pressure to
make sequels didn't really have ideas
for sequels it was a standalone idea
right and so they manufactured sequels
in order to me there
none of that would exist it would all be
labors of blood engaged in with people
and and and collaborated in by people
who believed in the thing for the thing
not because of its commercial potential
but believed in the thing for thing and
and that's what it looks like now how
the you produced that I have no
idea but that's that's what it looks
like all right
and I want to share I have thoughts that
boys happy for other people to go first
if they want to alright I will go my
version of an ideal entertainment media
world would be one where anyone can
create their own media that you have
access to the filming equipment you have
access to creating the team so any story
you want to tell you can tell and you
have access to the education so you can
get better at it right get better at
directing get better at acting whatever
that is but that it's open to everyone
where you can rent ie for free from the
library at cost of replacing it the
equipment as well as the editing and
every and everything else and on a
larger scale of what gets produced I
want to be able to put my money in
beforehand and say hey I want more
representation I want more queer
representation
I want more disabilities and therefore
be able to possibly vote on scripts that
do look like that gee that looked like
they're better because right now no
we're not getting going back to the
previous one but this idea that media
and information is very injured
intertwined you can't actually have one
with you watch a movie you're getting
all of that information even if you
don't you're not there for it you're not
there for information so to have the
product placement and all of the
subliminal stuff be less subliminal more
on the surface because it's it's if
you're there for your art you're not
putting coke there if you're drinking
Coke you're making a statement right
it's part of the actual actual process
so then what is what is that statement
having the ability as a city to choose
what actually is worth getting made in
Vancouver streets because let me tell
you if you shut down my street for
sharknado eight no but if you're
shutting it down for a new you know
seven years of slave or something that
like is gonna have some kind of impact
okay and like who makes that that
decision will Vancouverites right like
who makes the decision on what gets
funded the consumer at the I do what I
am I willing to put ten bucks into seen
this movie before it's ever made right
before they put in two hundred million
dollars to make the next Star Wars am I
willing to pay for it well yes of course
and then for more fringe ones it would
be hey it doesn't have content that I
actually want to watch it and you'd have
I think you'd have tons of content
and then I want to know what's gonna
work for me what's gonna be up in
alignment with me if I like Star Trek
what else will I like if I like I've
just been refined just watched the great
which got very bad reviews and I
actually really liked it it was like
Catherine the Great but in this that
time period but this time period it was
mashed-up which I know some people hate
so that would be my version of an ideal
media source is everyone has access to
it and yet
together we can fund the more costly
ones both by public will of can we use
the streets what gets films where is if
you need the streets to be shut down to
film you're gonna need to get city
rights which means we need to have
priority which projects are most
important and fun as an individual I can
make any art I want and have get help
creating those teams so that is what my
version would look like and I think we
have the right technology we could start
that within five years Daniel or Shiloh
would you like to share on what you what
if that brought up anything this needs
to be a whole brand vision or anything
feel like a little little thing I feel
like I have to bow out to the people who
spent some time thinking about this
topic like I've done very little on this
topic myself I really like that idea of
the library thing access to equipment
for everyone that's pretty cool
funding something before it's made I
mean I've seen some examples of stuff
like that so that's cool it's kind of
tricky because you have some talented
people that like you know some things
are hard to describe before they're made
like I loved the matrix could I could
they have described that well enough for
me to have funded it beforehand I don't
know but I think that's a cool idea
another thing that came in mind was like
you know what if we had a system where
like you know more proceeds from films
went to causes like you knew oh if I'm
seeing this film I had this idea that it
was going
um that the proceeds were going to
something I cared about or you could
have like a theater that like show films
in that way that might be a partial help
I like some of the stuff I heard so far
I guess that's it um I get to Jubilee I
when I picture kind of like this
alternative media system that's
connected with people kind of like a
humanitarian like in my world it's a
humanitarian counterbalancing system to
capitalism so it is exactly what you're
saying where we do have access to all of
these types of things to make art and
media freely collectively but I really
like the idea of like the meta currency
showing these connections so we can kind
of start to see what like a lot of
people don't really think about when
they're seeing a coke can on TV that
it's triggering them to drink coke it's
just because a lot of times media for us
is a way to relax so we're kind of
checking out we're kind of like don't
want to have to think anymore and when
we're being triggered by things like
that it'd be really cool to see a system
that shows like you're saying the
positive stuff and triggers us to do
more recycling or just be more creative
in our ways of being sustainable and
having a way to show that in the
currency so I don't know you guys
watched some of Raymond's um more recent
videos but there was somebody on his one
of his calls that I think I'm probably
really butchering it but I think they're
like a media positive media type company
then they're trying to get these
positive things out but also gang I
really like what you said about like a
theater that's dedicated to these more
positive works or works that are going
to stimulate us in a way that's positive
humanity I think that's super cool too
yeah I will just think I wanted one of
the things I would like to see in the
future and starting to happen out like
the diversity in the sex that's in media
and the main characters that are in
media those things are the ones that
like when when queer people were first
more often in the limelight their
secondary roles right it's the same with
people with disabilities unless it's
focused on your disability story you're
not a main character right unless it's
focusing on your emergence into being
the hero or heroine you don't get to be
the hero or heroine and then because
life imitates art were attracted to
people that look like the leading roles
and the more we have new people in those
leading roles the more our diversity of
Attraction opens and then with things
like consents and things like even like
safe sex when they're not part of the
media right when you just like kiss and
then you're laying in bed it's like wait
what about the condom what about that
awkward conversation what about the like
you know like making consent sexy
instead of the idea that oh that's
boring
well that right because we haven't seen
at movies as much you know I mean now
it's starting to get it and you can see
okay well this is actually that can be
really sexy and having more of those
conversations without it because then
there's also the other side of like when
I look at complex characters like Dexter
and Nurse Jackie did they come about
because we were ready for it as a
society and therefore we're more complex
or or did they allow us to accept like
chicken or egg right what happens first
like because 10 years before Dexter came
out we wouldn't have been ready for
Dexter and now even if Dexter came out
again to be like a same ol single right
like there's so many now but it's it
becomes anyway I know anyone else have
any thoughts and what they would like it
to look like in the future with millions
of dollars and everyone participating
and then we'll get on to the town people
who chase it possible I'm just gonna
push back a little bit but just before I
do I'd really like the idea of the
libraries you know having having the
studios and the camera equipment and the
audio equipment and
paintbrushes and canvases and
blah-blah-blah-blah-blah you know
there's just there for anyone to use
along with access to instruction how to
improve all of that kind of thing I
think that's all of that yes that's
exactly how people who have labors of
love can can you know and but don't have
money so that Kenan Kenan can actually
bring that into the world so I love all
of that there's a couple of things that
I said that I kind of like the idea but
I also see problems with right so the
idea of font text is a really good
example right if you'd put that out in
the world and sought funding for it what
you want to make a you want to make a
you know like a serial killer
violent serial killer you want to make
in the hero of a show no way
there's no way I'm putting money into
that right all of the righteous
indignation would have come up and and
no way that ever gets funded so I think
the notion of funding stuff from the
eventual audience I think is I think is
a I I think it really restricts the
possibility of what can be made right
rather giving the people access but
either I just let them make what they
want and then people like it and they
like it they don't like it they don't
like it and let it be upregulated and
downregulated you know post-production I
think there was there was one other
thing as well the other thing no I can't
remember so kinda been that important
are we still are - what well something
that comes to mind is this question that
I've been studying over the past month
and a half which is asking does this
matter
and I wonder if that's a good way to
like set our compass on things I mean
he's like does the movie matter like to
be made or whatever you're doing does it
matter so like I'm sort of thinking for
instance like I care a lot about local
gardening and like food security and
like why do we have all these lawns kind
of thing and at least where I live and
so but people really love comedy so like
you know and I I get that and so what if
you had
like a show that had all the comedic I
don't know just silliness and whatever
that people loved but you have to ask
okay what is the context that I'm gonna
do this in because that matters I could
do a comedy show in any sort of context
you know sort of like a Cheers or
surrounding a bar or surrounding her I
don't know an office or an oil rig or
whatever but what if I did a comedy show
and I said okay so what matters people
like comedy it's great sure fine what if
I surrounded it in like urban gardening
and like there you go make it cool make
it fun so I guess the what really
matters here has helped me a compass and
to me that is part of the crowd funny
beforehand but I also get what Eric is
saying I there's one of my favorite
stories for hunger games before Hunger
Games was making people like well well
no one wants to watch a story about a
female lead that isn't all about the
romance I mean yes there's romance in
Hunger Games but it's and then it came
out and it was blockbuster they were
like oh actually women are half the
population and they also want to see
themselves as heroes they also want to
be the main character and and then the
investors started and then there's a lot
of female content that's the main
character but as a woman I would have
known I wanted to go see Katniss because
I've read the books so I would have
funded Hunger Games for sure and so
would the people who do the books and so
there's a certain amount of the audience
knowing but also it could have really
been shitty right even though the books
are good the movie itself it's happened
time and time again there were it's it's
bad right so it's it is it doesn't mean
you get good art necessarily know it has
to be a new a new mechanism for not just
what how do we fund it but how do we
also get the best out there which might
mean instead of what is it called in
Hollywood when you get a on a contract
to make the film you have the option is
it an option the option to make the film
but instead of it being an option right
I own the option for making Hunger Games
that we say hey Hunger Games wants to be
made and we want
we made into a movie whoo having bunch
people have the scripts having a bunch
of people see what their cinematic views
look like and then the people who like
Hunger Games voting on which one they
want to make the movie and then that
person makes the movie at least we have
some amount of saying whether it fails
or not all right and we are over time
for getting onto my favorite portion
does anyone have any closing statements
now that I've taken up just I've put a
link in the in the chat window
especially for you Daniel but just
because of what you were talking about a
minute ago putting a TV opening a comedy
in the context of there's a show a
button made by the BBC years and years
ago it's decades old called The Good
Life it's a really really excellent
sitcom and it is exactly that it's a
really good sitcom really nice character
setting exactly that they leave their
jobs and and use their garden to raise
chickens and grow vegetables and and all
that and this was made 40 years ago I
mean it was really ahead of its time and
it's an excellent show I highly
recommend watching it I put the plate up
put a playlist in the chat window for
you nice and into what's currently on
Netflix there's more current one of two
people quitting their jobs and moving
it's a comedy so just before we move on
just that it's it's reads I think it's
only fair to say that a lot of really
really really good stuff does get made
in this world you know I mean I mean
there's a lot of really in all domains
of media entertainment there is a lot of
really excellent stuff produced so yeah
that shouldn't be forgotten the problem
is that when something good is produced
it's immediately captured by you know
the animals wanting to feed off of it
you know I mean it comes and becomes
something ugly
so yes anyway let's move on all right so
the adjacent possible so in the area of
entertainment and media what could
10,000 people and $100,000 do to improve
our media lives right our entertainment
lives for those 10,000 people not
necessarily the world or maybe those
10,000 people are the filmmakers they
can be in various groups of 10 thousand
people but 10,000 people and $100,000
what could we do with that you'll think
Jubilee it's perfect I mean it's
actually perfect for that 10,000 people
each to putting in $10 to buy $100,000
worth of equipment $100,000 as a
meaningful spend if you're going to be
buying all
video equipment that is a meaningful you
can buy good stuff with that right and
and the reasonable amount of it that
those 10,000 people could have access to
right so that you did they collectively
have access to that which way they have
collectively purchased simple I love it
love that expect don't forget anywhere
near enough money like 10,000 people put
money $10 in to get access to equipment
there's now 10,000 people who want that
equipment yeah but they don't all want
it all at once that's the point right
they they own it collectively and they
figure out some way of you know library
yet yeah and and and I agree there's
some logistical difficulties to be
figured out but in principle I
absolutely think it works at that kind
of scale I think it does work what could
happen well we could do with a hundred
thousand ten thousand is actually start
a library with existing equipment
meaning all the people who have this
equipment like an Airbnb for khurana
equipment right that you get rented out
what that cost or you know like if it's
broken it's insurance like Airbnb that
there's a way to use existing what
people own and either they donate it for
credit or they have it in the library
system so they maybe have priority on
other equipment that they get to use but
there's a lot of equipment that just
sits there and used because and then
maybe you have to have a certain skill
sets we will be use that equipment right
when you're starting you're using like
the very durable maybe not so great but
as you prove your your skills you can
and your skill more likely less in film
and morning not breaking it right boring
not ruining the equipment for the for
the rest of the people
I think there's all
so something what is it called the test
the black something test it's it's it's
a feminine it's due to I think after
this easy due to women talk in the movie
on something other than men to women
talking to each other man could be
presence or not they're talking about
something other than a man that is the
BLET role test or whatever and very few
movies toss it that is how sad it is but
having some something like that with
every movie every script this been made
having it show right what are the white
people say versus the black people what
are the females and the males but it's
like just even having that catalog now
could we do that for $100,000 I don't
know we really like movies people like
writing them out the scripts already
available right so maybe it's already
there it's just about creating the the
robot that doesn't because then I also
have access to if I do want queer
contents right here all the gay
characters and gay people may have said
yes I like this one and not this one
right this is a good representation this
is a bad representation I want to see
somebody in a movie who has autism but
actually has autism right like the actor
has autism different than like um Wayne
man who played Rain Man right he's not
he's not autistic
thank you that there is like they're
different right Rain Man is a very
important movie but not if it was made
today it would be actually it's what
happens all the time not autistic actors
play autistic people all the time but to
be able to find that content within what
exists how do I find mine
knowing what projects so there's like
three different projects a Kickstarter
type thing for movies of hey I have this
thing how do i fund it how do we get the
cost down how do we coordinate on and if
we want it to actually be made sure
equipment I'm gonna say just in my
perfect world um we do have hubs in
every community that are like our
community centers or really the Commons
so I do think if we eventually have the
Commons as a valued resource and we
actually value it we would have the
possibility to have these types of
libraries in every community and in some
ways people could donate their stuff
that they have maybe you have stuff you
and then people can learn on it but also
you could do fundraisers to improve
those libraries if you're getting a lot
of use out of them but by using using it
as a value system within your community
you could see the interconnectivity and
how the arts really enhance our lives
and I think that would also lead to a
lot less sex in movies and I'm probably
sounding very old and nasty because I
don't know it's just too much there's so
much I feel so uncomfortable and I have
friends with young kids they can't watch
a movie without it being uncomfortable
because there's like just so much sex in
your face and it feels like it's because
of these perverts in Hollywood or
whatever that are directing or producing
all this content for more of that
activity and I just feel like if it was
if we had our hubs and we had these
types of media libraries and it was more
like you have to be at least you don't
have to be but a lot of the content
would be more family-friendly because
people in families were participating in
making it my little something a poke no
that's a media for kids where especially
LGBT content because all the parents
that are up in arms about like how dare
you have two moms right
finding dory has two women pushing a
carriage in Central Park that are
neither in the background they were
freaking out like you know your main
character as a lesbian right like the
actress but whatever that there's enough
parents who are LGBT and have kids who
are LGBTQ plus that we can fund that
like who cares what if Pixar and Disney
make it can we make it but then it
becomes like I don't know bad media like
it's it's like if you create queer
content for kids it's gonna be bad queer
content for kids but that's ok I'm ok
with that
I'd rather bad pure content they know
queer content but my eventual goal I
want to be able to have the like it not
to be a big deal right have heroes that
are every ability and every look and
every and have and have it be no big
deal not this up in arms oh my god you
you had a autistic person be the main
the main character yeah cuz I'm autistic
and I'm the main character in my life
you know my place I could direct roles a
lot of the time to both I think that's
kind of the key for like having that
equity of access to things is the
library or Commons just say the live you
know your film library for equipment is
not they don't have a voice in what gets
made they're just giving the equipment
and like so you know because you have
different opinions on all these things
you know what you know right or wrong or
whatever like that's just a fact but
you're you know the the library can lend
these things out but isn't like
contributing to producing or profiting
from whatever gets made you know I could
you you know someone could take that
equipment when it's their turn and make
something that you know was I don't know
more traditional or something and you
could be like all it didn't you
have enough of this type of diversity
but you know that's on them it's not on
the library so I think that is like when
we make media for profit somebody in a
boardroom decides it it's for profit
right is is the lead character white
male and able-bodied then we couldn't
possibly make this right
no it's gonna be bare as we are in the
world right so if we are making it I
could choose to make a white male
character because I think it's gonna be
more profitable but it's not gonna be my
art it's not gonna be touching my heart
and telling my story and do you that so
it's gonna be kind of crap whereas if I
can tell my story writer the stories
that are more similar to mine there's
going to be more diversity out there so
I like the idea of allowing people to
create their own will learn and not
putting restrictions on that what we've
done is because we're afraid to do
anything radical or that seems
impossible like I'm talking about where
the big money is we've kind of distilled
things down to be relatively safe in all
these different realms like in on the
sex stuff or the non sex stuff or I mean
there's all sorts of things about
violence and we push the edge on that as
well so but if you have it seems to me
like if you have an opinion that Mike
could get people riled up
but you've got to just go with the
lowest common denominator and just like
keep putting out superhero movies
because like not likely to offend
anybody with that I know some people who
are in there in Christian filmmaking and
like so even that side you know they
can't was very hard for them to get
traction on funding or advertising mean
they they end up making their stuff but
they can't you know no one puts it on
their platforms someone got something on
Amazon Prime and so like I don't need to
say whether I agree or disagree with
like the views that they're saying they
have in their films
but it's same kind of thing it's too
touchy and so they have so then you have
these networks that I don't know like if
there's LGBT something like that
networks but you know those folks the
they put together like what I don't know
what it's called shine media or
something's like Netflix just for
Christian films $6.99 a month or
something because like we can't get our
stuff on that we just got to make our
own dang platform for our for our people
to put their stuff on and maybe that's
what's gonna happen is we're just gonna
continue to have more and more different
platforms um is that like more echo
chambers or something I don't know but
for whatever is going on it seems like
yeah we just keep going to the lowest
common denominator because you can't do
anything too exciting even even big
companies that we know about like
Jubilee you're mentioning you know a
company like Disney or Pixar if they do
something that is a little bit edgy
pushing the envelope progressively I
mean gosh all they need is enough voices
to say we're gonna stop we're gonna drop
your your subscription or you know we're
not gonna like it doesn't even have to
be in every single film but you want to
make one film that has a message and all
of a sudden you've got people saying
your whole company is like this and we
can't support you and whatever and so
like companies are afraid to lose I
don't know what it is well like lose
subscribers or something but they're
they're fan based or they're very loyal
fanbase they don't want to risk risk
profit what are the other things coming
up we're talking is there's a sweb site
that exists it's called the Common Sense
Media go to it all the time for kids
it's about kids it's it's what do adults
say is the age you should watch this on
what do kids say is the age you should
watch this arm then it talks
sex and violence and we're working
everything else and so it's easier to
find things that are suitable for your
family having something like that for
all media where it isn't about like if
you have a trigger warning for your own
personal self here are the parts to skip
and if you skip this part here's what
you need to know from it right like
therefore you could say okay well well
you're not gonna see any of the sex
scenes right you're not gonna see any
violence or in my kids case you can
handle violence but not blood so it's
like knowing when there's gonna be blood
and and shutting her eyes or you know
just skipping those parts well still
getting the plot points could help
people still is that you know so it's
like I don't need everyone so don't have
LGBT content or to have that to be to
content but if I want my kid not to see
a baby I can censor that I don't yeah
that I mean I could see that I mean what
if you like one to watch you know Lord
of the Rings but was that already pg-13
I don't know there's like some
particular like you know most of it's
good but I just don't want these certain
things where like its Gore like I want
the whole movie just like these certain
things that push that envelope for me on
gore and like just take that out is that
okay that'd be like a really cool
solution I know how you do it but and
you know it's happening right because
it's all you just like deleting scenes
you're just like you know you're not
watching this scene and go to the next
one and the more technology it would be
more just information of where you skip
go from this point to this point
technology
excuse me right along with this
technology comes the ability for other
people to say I don't want to see any of
the scenes with black people in or I
don't want to see any you know I mean
and and so I I'm not sure because life
does contain violence and sex and gore
and blood sometimes you know and and to
exclude it in all cases
I agree there's too much of it I'm not
not disputing that at all that it's
routier Thyssen is way too often use I
that I'm not arguing for a second
however to eliminate it completely to
have a bit of software that would
eliminate all traces
that which you do not wish to see from
from from your feet I don't I don't
think that's healthy I don't think
that's good either
it just helps with the idea that you get
to cater your own right so you get a
change like Daniel saying they just as a
self-created echo chamber and nothing
other than the fluffy beautiful things
that you want to see in life and make it
into your bubble you know what I mean
that's that's not healthy I don't think
anyway my dad that's okay but I also
think it's like you have to be aware of
what you want and don't want right so if
your own we're like why would you even
put it I don't want black people in at
all and you put that into the algorithm
and like what show is watchable that's
made in the last 30 years right like
you're like all of these scenes aren't
in there you get the beginning and the
credits that's it like it's not what is
there left to watch when you take all
the sec say well this is great you're
not gonna watch those ones you know this
is sort of related because sometimes we
have really great stories that are
meaningful but the only way that they
are able to get any traction in a larger
population is to have these exciting
things and so you have to have that
along with the story for anyone to even
like put it in theaters that might be
like a little bit more precise on what's
going on I mean like so let's say you
just had a great wonderful meaningful
story that could like actually help
someone be encouraged or something but
if you don't include some of these
really edgy things which I'm not like I
mean I'm pretty edgy like I like this
thing but some people won't you know if
you don't include them it's not gonna
get traction in a larger world and like
maybe that's part of the thing but to go
back to the original problem with the
$10,000 or $100,000 thing showing films
that have a particular cause like there
is another thing you could possibly do
me and some friends we're talking
we're throwing around the idea of
starting a documentary Club at one point
we didn't really have the space to do it
but we had a lot of documentaries we all
liked watching we did one showing at a
church that let us use their space and
we had like 20 people show up and that
was pretty cool
and that was last year kind of want to
do it again and now we're like in the
pandemic and we're hoping to do another
one in the spring but we thought man
what if we had a space and we could like
once a month we show a documentary and
like have people come and throw in five
bucks if you got it if you don't hang
out anyways have a little pizza whatever
you want to sustainably do I don't know
but um that could be a fun way we did
like a Q&A thing afterwards so like it
kind of got people a little bit
connected what do you think let people
just have a moment to agree or disagree
and the documentary Club
I don't know hundred thousand dollars
you commit by a building or rent space
with that maybe in Toronto to talk about
a cure anything yet the person but ya
know having something like that words I
mean they do that a co-hosting all the
time or their get a documentary and
watch it together and then discuss it
it's less of it but knowing when that
was happening where you could go to do
that right and each other having
discussion around it it would be a cool
tool for sure
how did like that - and I kind of see
that as part of this new system arising
with the Commons hopefully so we don't
have to always buy a whole theater but
we have space that we can schedule and
do that kind of thing but what I really
like about and I probably doesn't fit
into the hundred thousand dollars ten
thousand people but if we do create this
alternative value system we do then have
the feedback loops that we need because
we might think that we have to add all
this violence and gore to our movies to
get people to watch it but maybe that's
just what they've been telling us maybe
that's not necessarily true and that's
how they keep their funding and then
how they get so maybe if we had more
feedback loops about what we are
watching and ways like I don't really
like the sensory neither but if you had
a way to I don't know vote on the fact
that this has you know ninety percent
sex and we may be needed thirty percent
and we could have got the point across
if there was a way to have that so
people can realize maybe what we're
being told what we need isn't really
what we need or even want and so that's
one part one other thing I can't
remember I forgot already go I just want
to throw that out there I think about I
think you have a good point on the
feedback loops I think that's one of the
things we're learning with YouTube we've
got lis these big corporate machines
that are so afraid to take risks that
they just like well this worked let's
keep doing that like what we're seeing
with YouTube especially with news media
is like they're freaking out they're
like oh wait a second so they're like
well the people can only handle 30
second sound bites two minute interviews
and like that so it works and that's it
and they didn't realize that people
could actually handle 20 minute videos
and that they would like that and so the
experimentation I think however you put
it was like that's really cool they
don't even know what actually how we've
changed because they can't really
experiment I just remember the last
thing I was going to say um Jubilee if
like if we are making our own media in
our neighborhoods or whatnot and we're
voting let's say on it or we're just
saying we love it it affected me and
then we just like to make it into a
bigger production our communities can
support it and we could find ways to
hurt to get people to engage in like
let's say we have a lot of local things
that we show in our movies so we're like
supporting our local businesses just by
showing them in our movies and we kind
of are tracking that with our currency
system so we can see the value you can
bring to your own community through that
and then in the bigger picture any
profits can go back to the community and
maybe at the Commons love
so it can like filter back out to the
community so okay it's a thing I would
just like a tool to know what to
binge-watch next I think when you're out
of content it's like like I want
something like this and be able to see
it that isn't related to like Netflix
telling me what I should watch or orders
some others I was like I want to know
what I want
sorry have you seen succession excellent
excellent oh really fantastic writing
fantastic acting very little sex
although there is a bit it's pretty ugly
in places you know what I mean like
horrible people but there's there's no
violence to speak of certainly no gore
but it's really horrible people like
rich people being horrible to each other
is it's it's excellent is really
excellent in a historical study
especially no no modern said I think
it's based loosely on the Murdock family
that's it looks to me like those plates
loosely on the Murdoch family so it's a
media tycoon who's getting old you know
I mean losing his grip on his empire his
children are sort of vying for position
to take over this kind of it's this sort
of thing it's really really fantastic
but I do really it's not something I
generate because it's the ones other
people like I don't like but like
watching this the great recently having
it I want to be able to put I want an
algorithm to tell me what I should watch
based on what I like and what I don't
like there's also a ton out there that I
keep trying sons of anarchy is one of
them I'm like everyone likes it I should
try these are one of the binge watch of
all ones and I'm like I shouldn't get
into either if it's any consolation I
couldn't get into Sons of Anarchy that
I've also been told by lots of people
it's really good
oh I did watch those son Life of Brian
but I'd never seen before
what an absolute work of genius there is
oh she's gone I was one of my absolute
favorite films of Life of Brian so so
brilliant it's back in succession it's
really really good
all right I will check that out but I
wanted to old it's one of the rare shows
I've seen and sit on TV in the last I
don't know used to be back in the day
there was lots and lots of good shows
around seems to me there's a lot more
and more and more crap you know what I
mean just churned out by Netflix from
prime and the real quality HBO type
stuff that used to come out pretty
regularly seems to dwindle I mean there
were loads it was six feet under there
was a Sopranos there was the news I mean
there were loads and loads and loads of
really good shows for a couple of
decades there and there is it's become
it's hard to find the good stuff in
amongst all the now so I think
there's so much of it that's the issue
like there's no way you can have water
like everyone watches the same five
shows like when I was a kid it's like
alright alright we're down to the last
two and a half minutes long right
everybody in the whole world
alright so for the last few minutes I'm
just gonna go around and everyone can
say the thing they think would be the
most powerful for 10,000 people and
$100,000 that we've discussed or
something new can come up in a moment
what do you think would be the most
impactful either whether you want to
answer for the world or for your life
for me the coolest idea is the notion of
a library and I don't see why it can't
be a Shilo said a combination of people
donating their own equipment and you
know using some of the hundred thousand
dollars to buy some swanky new equipment
right and and figuring out you know
figuring out the logistics of who gets
access when and for how long and blah
blah blah blah blah you know that that's
all gonna happen you figured out but
this is good right this creates
collaboration and friendships and
relationships within those 10,000 people
right you know in order to negotiate
this you're gonna have to you have to
figure out ways to get on with each
other so yeah that seems to me to be an
up and down and sideways really
excellent solution does its own solves
the problem it seeks to solve class has
a whole bunch of of knock-on benefits
that seems to me to be the my top choice
are you sure I'm just going
do where I initially started I think
this conversation wasn't about social
media I think sources is way bigger
problem than meets other things like by
far but on this topic I guess I I guess
I could see yeah like a well funded
documentary clock making a really big
impact there are people making amazing
documentaries giving them a better
platform to show those ones that already
exist making it fun um making it you
know you have refreshments it's not the
theatre that a conscious theatre what
about that like everything you guys are
saying I couldn't really hear you
Jubilee
I'm gonna just add I love what you guys
are all talking about thank you
my most impactful one I think just
because I'm not a filmmaker so I would
have less impact than the library thing
although I think worldwide that would be
most impactful and great for media in
general for me I would like to have
access to what diversity exists in roles
and just the data behind that how many
how many words are spoken how many
because we can do a lot with that data
it's just data and then we can say hey
are we getting better are we getting
more diversity how do I find roles that
not to play but to watch so that would
be my most or or something that sensors
for more for my child so that I can say
hey I don't want these scenes to be in
here I want to try watching this and see
if it's okay for her but not with these
scenes it's something like Lord of the
Rings or something so that would be the
most impactful so this is like I said
it's a two-parter although once I go
punch in social media I was like that's
weird that that was and it's not a
three-parter with social media being one
of them I think it's because yeah social
media permeates all of them that it's
like we need a whole new platform and
that is partly what we are doing the
second part is on Saturday on the
together tech channel we're talking
about media the information side of it
because Bentley Adriel have sets making
projects and my project
solution making and three of us for
there last week and it was just the
three of us for like let's do this this
week and so that is what we're doing if
there's more than just like this many
people showing up we're actually gonna
break into two groups and Adriel will
run one of them and I'll run one of them
so I'm excited to do that if that many
people show up so the link to that is in
the description for this video to watch
it you want to participate contact me in
all the ways they do people contact me
you know Facebook all that fun stuff
alright and I will see you
we'll see you next week for the next
Aleutian raising